All right, who here has heard of view use?
Yay, okay, so we got a we got some people here and then there are obviously some who haven't and so this is the one
Composable library. I tell everyone as much as I keep in the can because
It just represents this incredible collection of
What possibilities are with composables, right?
So if you're looking for examples of how composables could be written
I'd not sure there's really a better library to stare at because what they've essentially done if you don't know if you use is is
It's taken all the core functionality of like browsers and stuff and made it basically they've they've made everything
Reactive so it's ready to be used for view so
You know again they say show don't tell so the first thing so
Has anyone here ever implemented local storage by themselves? Yeah, they've is not terrible
But it's a little verbose and so what's cool is that they have this thing called use storage
And use storage essentially you wrap the you wrap instead of doing like something rough you just say
My thing like flag you storage you give it a key of whatever you want the local storage to store it
A under right because we're just gonna achieve it and then whatever value you want
And then after that flag just becomes this reactive ref that like does and then whenever it changes it updates the local storage and it's fantastic
And so the reason this is also particularly cool is because what this means is
It's a little it's not as effective in this particular demo because we technically have it back in that's saving data
But you can to give you an example
If we look at the task store
There we have here
You'll notice here the right now is just a regular
Reactive array
But if you were to import use storage
From view use core like this and you just wrapped it I think I can do it like this
Has
Think that works yeah
Dean okay, oh by the way
You see that maybe refer together
So more commonly I think seeing in libraries I think it's where we're seeing it because they just don't know what their users are gonna do
So what's cool about this then is that now that you have this all you've done is you've wrapped instead of just making it a normal ref
You've wrapped you storage to it and so now if we go to our site
and go to our tasks
You see here inside of your application
We bring this up so it's easier if I want to see
Look at that
All your stuff there it's fantastic and so if you're working on just a client side rendered app you don't have access to a database
And you want to be to like save your stuff in between sessions
This is a really cheap and easy way to do so like it's not quite a local database
But honestly, I think it'll get you pretty darn far
Being able to do that especially if you just you know cookie ideas whatever
It makes it just so easy and so to be clear though the default is
local storage but
You can see here
And this is the pattern that I want to talk about next
That they actually make it easy for you to then like configure things
So for example
See
Where's it use other storage shows can be specified via third argument right so where is that third argument so here's an example
Where they've given you like here's your key here's your object and then they actually have what they call like a serializer
So they actually give you the option to determine how your data is being pars so you have some custom
You know tree walker thing that like you know
I've got a Jason that probably stays in our tree and find that's fairly standard
But you know you might have some unique things that you're doing you can walk in there and it'll it basically accepts those things
And so I guess for the I'll switch back to this in just a second
The pattern here that we're talking about is ultimately what is called a um
Like the options parameter object and so to quickly just give you an overview what I mean by this
Is that a lot of times when people are writing
Composable although this really does apply to I think JavaScript as a whole like when you're architecting your for example
We were just using use fetch earlier, right? That's what we were doing
It's easy for developers to get carried away because they're like oh, there's your elders the methods, you know
There's like the body type whatever and they kind of like before you know it
There are some methods signatures that are just like you know so many arguments long and the problem with this
Even with this three alone is that you have to remember which order they're in
Right and so the the options parameter object
Basically tries to encourage developers to think more along the lines that like
Call it like the rule of thumb being that your first you can have
The rule of thumb is the first two parameters which are commonly used say in this particular case like you're on your methods
Those are so common that like cool those are the required ones that I want you to memorize
But if I have stuff like body type and whatever, this is really an options object
And instead of the options object you can then say like you know if you have like you know body
What would have for me and then it was like JSON whatever
You can then like expose additional functionality through this part
And so it's this idea of trying to keep your signatures lower so that obviously they're easier to understand and then by doing so
You then unlock what you see here inside of you use
Which is that they ultimately let me pick one for example
Use Ref History
Okay, let me fund this up so you'd see probably
This is how the controls
So what we see here right is use Ref History
Comes on in it takes in your counter and then what it does is it exposes additional functionality
that then can be used
Basically like without having you configure a bunch of stuff
So this is also called like a controls pattern and so typically like you can assume that like it it normally
allows you to
Increment document and whatnot
But then it exposes additional functionality for undo and redo should you choose to like expose it
And so it's kind of like thinking of it like overloading a JavaScript function where you have like a basic implementation
Where it like does the simplest thing you want it to do and then when the user
Configures again, I'm not sure where
There wasn't an example that was let me just write the signature for you
Was essentially like this it was like I was
So by default
It was something like this it was like use play video
Right and so use play video by default
Assume that you would basically give it like again, let's say video URL
And then when you basically grab the video and you played it or you've basically ran the
Function you would play the video because that's what you would be but by normally default do and then what it did was interesting enough
It would it allow you to do something like controls equals true and
What that happened was it would then instead of assuming you wanted to play
It would all of a sudden expose a play a pause stop and like fast forward for example
And we give you fine grain like control over how the function worked
And so I'm not telling you whether you should do it this way one way or another
But I I have found it to be an interesting way to allow
Users to progressively enhance complexity in their functions
Because normally I think we're used to just kind of writing new functions every time you want new functionality
But this way with this kind of controls true flag or via like the options parameter
It gives you a way of thinking about things from like a okay nine out of ten times users are doing this
One out of ten times they need more granular control. This is how we're gonna expose it to them
So this is like a pattern that's kind of interesting
That's wanted to share with you
Use media controls it was it in that one I was I didn't want to use might be what you're thinking of
Maybe you know it's funny. Yeah, it might be that one
You said use media controls yeah has a source and then it has a whole bunch of options
And then if you just click it is this playing and yeah, I think this is this is similar. Yeah, there's so much fun stuff in here to play with
So for example, one of the things I've used a lot is like use color mode
It basically uses the browser API to automatically detect whether what kind of theme you prefer like dark
And then since that's something you have to manage anyways. It's just really convenient to have